[Blood River]
[Based on the novel of the same name from Zhou Munan's Youth in Jianghu series]
[Available on fanqienovel.com & bkneng.com]
[Episode 26]
Senior.
You've spent all these years
practicing martial arts, huh?
To save lives,
a physician must know how to protect himself first.
Senior.
What a pity. You're being naive.
Senior, oh, senior.
I never thought
you'd end up falling into my hands.
Do we kill him now?
Take him back to the Tang Clan first.
[He-Yu Clinic]
My good girl.
Come.
Let's go to the lantern festival.
Why has this courtyard
been quiet
since Su Muyu's departure?
Where is that cheerful daughter of mine?
I just think
Su Muyu
tends to overthink
and keep things to himself.
And he's fine
making himself mentally exhausted.
Compared to Su Changhe,
Su Muyu isn't half bad.
You could figure out what's on Su Muyu's mind,
but you would never do the same
to Su Changhe.
I could never,
and I don't get my head around it.
Just like now.
I just don't get it.
Why
did we part ways
time and time again?
My silly daughter.
You're never meant to be.
They belong to the Blood River.
Though
you've seen each other
as friends,
they're Blood River members after all.
The Blood River remains
unacceptable in this world.
It's not that they don't see you as a friend.
It's just that...
They don't want
to get you involved
when they're in danger.
There, there.
Don't be sad.
Jin City
is a nice place.
Mount Wangcheng is nearby.
Don't you want to meet
that Taoist you admire?
Well...
Forget it.
After all,
the idea of Master Mu paying the Wangchengshan Sect a visit
sounds rather frightening.
Turns out Master Mu
is a young lad.
Looks like
we can't visit the Wangchengshan Sect even if we want to.
Our friend from the Tang Clan is here.
I don't think we're friends yet.
There's no telling what.
Death Summons, huh?
Is this how the Tang Clan
entertains a guest?
Since this is your turf,
why must you
hide your faces
in our presence?
Where is Tang Linghuang?
He agreed to see us.
Even if he left the city to greet us in advance,
why isn't he here?
What makes you think
that I'm not Tang Linghuang?
If you were Tang Linghuang,
this peach wood sword of mine
would've turned to dust now.
Are you saying
that I'm less than him?
I never said so.
Xuewei.
How dare you try to poison us.
How pathetic.
Pathetic?
My family has practiced dark arts for years.
When it comes to using poison,
we're as good as
your clan.
Activate the array.
The poisonous fog opens the gates to the underworld.
Through the art of sigils, the true flame is revealed.
That's the Tang Clan's Fourfold Blackwater Formation.
Trying to use your poison in the presence of Poisonous Blossom?
Ridiculous.
This is awe-inspiring.
This lady
has managed to refine
her poisoning technique to such an exquisite state.
Poisoning technique?
It's more than that.
I bet this will
get more interesting.
Mister.
Our presence here means no harm.
Why must you
resort to violence?
You're from the Blood River,
so there's nothing good.
I got it now.
That lady
is a poisonous person.
I never expected the Mu family of Blood River
would manage to train
such a poisonous person.
That's Poisonous Blossom from the Blood River.
I want her.
I get it now.
The Tang Clan
is under someone else's control.
That's why you're not happy
about our presence here.
Nonsense!
My body is all poisonous.
You sure are courting death.
What's going on?
Mu Qingyang!
Xuewei!
Blood blooms beneath the skin.
A single cut means instant death.
Why do they remain unharmed?
Could it be
that there are poisonous persons like Xuewei
in the Tang Clan?
I get it.
Both of them
are the drugged puppets
mentioned in Patriarch's letter!
They're numb.
They show no fear.
And they're immune to all poisons.
I see it now!
Xuewei!
How rare.
I never thought there'd be
such a perfect poisonous person in this world.
Who are you?
You'll find out soon.
Take her away.
Xuewei!
Never underestimate the Tang Clan.
My good daughter.
Where did this little white snake come from?
That's a Death-Chasing Serpent.
Death-Chasing Serpent?
Every disciple of the Medicine King Valley
keeps one for protection.
When faced with deadly danger,
we secretly release the Death-Chasing Serpent.
It will crawl over mountains and rivers,
traveling all the way
to find another disciple of the Valley.
I never knew about that.
Baicao
is always such a cautious one.
Could he have fallen into danger?
[Jin City]
"Heaven parts once to birth the mortal realm.
From a thousand trees and rivers, life begins anew.
Grass, woods, and clouds all tinted violet.
Even wind and moon can't touch its wild grace."
That poem was written
by your favorite Sword Poet Deity.
It describes Jin City itself.
Now that you've stepped into it,
how do you feel?
I've been here
many years ago.
What were you here for?
I was the Umbrella Ghost of the Blood River then.
What else could it have been for?
I see.
[Jingsi Teahouse]
What are they doing, Su Muyu?
Do you get it?
Thirty Thousand.
Four Bamboos.
It's called Mahjong.
It's very popular here in Jin City.
They drink tea and play mahjong,
or pull up a stool
and gather around for a "Dragon Gate Array" session.
That's daily life for the people of Jin City.
Dragon Gate Array?
Is that some powerful formation?
Well, you could say that.
Their posture when gathered together
looks just like General Xue of the old dynasty
when he encircled the northern tribes.
But with Tang Clan guarding inside Jin City
and Wangchengshan Sect defending the outside,
peace has reigned for years.
Why would Jin City folk
need to set up any "Dragon Gate Array"?
It's just a saying.
They just gather to gossip
about whatever's been happening lately.
So basically, they're just bragging together.
Su Muyu.
Why is it that I'm the one asking questions,
and you're answering them?
Have we switched roles all of a sudden?
Wasn't it you
who always knew nothing
about stuff?
Back then, to deal with a powerful enemy,
I stayed in Jin City for three whole months.
So I got to know this place quite well.
Mahjong!
That means you've won, right?
Of course I have.
[Lei Yunhe, Lei Clan]
128 points in total! Pay up!
That's sheer luck, brat.
Come on, again!
Still playing?
Who are you? We're in a game!
We have no time to entertain you.
Master Mu.
You brat!
What's that supposed to mean?
Is he insulting me?
That's the slang here.
He was just greeting you warmly.
How funny.
This gentleman sure is full of humor.
Brat.
If you hadn't sounded so sincere,
I'd have thought you were provoking me.
Master Mu.
Is that how you greet people here?
Patriarch and Master Su.
Why didn't you inform me of your presence here
in advance?
I could have made preparations early.
This friend of mine
stayed in Jin City for three months then.
You were the one who hosted him, weren't you?
Yes.
Yes, yes.
So you taught him to greet people
by calling them brat?
Well...
[Master Mu, Jin City Mole]
I was only joking
with Master Su.
I didn't expect Master Su
would take it seriously.
After that, I...
I...
I didn't explain it.
No wonder Liu Yilong seemed so furious
when I was having a duel with him
then.
That's actually an insult, huh?
Pardon me, I...
Because you always acted like
a polite assassin?
You even greet people before killing them.
I bet Liu Yilong was so mad
that he couldn't even hold his sword well
when you called him that.
That's enough.
All right, I'll stop laughing.
You mood changes faster than the weather here in Jin City.
Master Mu.
Yes, sir.
You said we came
without notice.
I was wrong.
Patriarch, Master Su.
With your status,
you can come and go as you please.
Why would you inform me of it?
That was a slip of the tongue.
I misspoke.
No.
What I mean is
I already told you so long ago.
In fact,
they've been waiting here
for us too.
Them?
Who?
One is Mu Xuewei.
Poisonous Blossom?
As the other one,
you haven't met him
after years of being stationed here in Jin City.
However,
he's now your family head.
And that's Mu Qingyang.
Well...
You haven't seen them before?
I swear.
I really haven't seen them.
If Mu family head
ever came to my teahouse,
how could I not know?
The situation looks bad.
I'd say it's very bad.
Changhe.
Where is Yumo?
Before entering the city,
she was still with us.
Yumo
went ahead of us
and infiltrated the Tang Clan.
She infiltrated the Tang Clan?
They say Tang Fort is nothing but dangerous.
But it doesn't seem hard to get into it.
[Tang Lian]
Who's that? How dare you intrude upon
[Disciple of Tang Lianyue]
Tang Clan's forbidden grounds.
So it's a young boy.
You're pretty agile.
Don't move.
Stay still
or don't blame me
for being merciless.
Who exactly are you?
That Fingertip Blade of yours seems nice.
And it looks somewhat familiar to me.
Who taught you that?
Why do you ask?
Are you threatening me?
I actually figured it out.
You're Tang Lianyue's disciple,
aren't you?
How do you know that?
I knew it.
Like master,
like disciple.
How foolish.
I just probed into it,
and you told me everything.
You tricked me?
You just asked me a question.
You asked who I am.
I can tell you now.
I am...
your master's future wife.
What?
You...
Do you want to get everyone here?
Rest assured.
Do I look like a bad person?
I really am your master's wife.
However...
Would someone like my master
have a woman he adores?
But even if he did have one,
he wouldn't tell us for sure.
What an adorable disciple.
What nonsense are you saying?
All right.
Well,
what's your name?
My name is Tang Lian.
Lian, as in lotus flower.
Your master is Tang Lianyue,
and you're Tang Lian.
How amusing.
Tell me where he is.
Take me to him.
Wait!
Even if my master has someone he loves,
what proof do you have
that you're the one?
You need proof for that?
Fine.
Looks familiar, doesn't it?
That's Master's Fingertip Blade!
Yes.
Your master gave it to me.
He said
it was our token of affection.
Do you believe me now?
Surely you don't think
a weak woman
like me
could have seized his personal weapon
by force, do you?
But...
Mistress.
My master has been in seclusion lately.
Even I haven't seen him for a long time.
Seclusion?
After entering the Lianyue Pavilion,
he hasn't come out since then.
Martial Uncle said
that he went into seclusion to cultivate.
Right there.
He's in seclusion because he doesn't know I'm here.
He'll show himself
if I go to him.
That won't do, Mistress.
There are two inner-hall martial uncles guarding outside the Lianyue Pavilion.
They're always strict when it comes to that,
even though you're close to Master.
I've asked to see Master several times,
but I was always turned away.
Is that so?
Mistress!
Mistress.
There's certainly something off
about Uncle Fulu and Uncle Tianlu.
What do you mean?
By seniority, those two
are considered Master's elders.
Why would they be guarding for him?
Only one of them did that.
Now both of them are here...
Could it be
that Master...
I'll go check on it.
Mistress!
Who's there?
Uncle Tianlu.
You're here too, Uncle Fulu.
It's you, Tang Lian.
Can't sleep again?
I'm missing my master,
so I'm here to have a look.
Your master is in seclusion.
Looks like
this seclusion of his
is truly important.
Martial Uncles, thank you
for staying up to guard him.
Fulu.
There was some noise above just now.
I'll go check on it.
What is he trying to do?
Stop!
This is…
Tang Lianyue.
Master!
Master.
How could this be?
This is…
Who are you?
Go!
Get help!
You must wait for my return.
No.
Why not?
No matter
how gifted the brat is,
he's as temperamental as his master.
Now
he already knows his master is trapped by us.
We can't let him live.
Hold on.
Only he and Tang Linghuang know
where the hidden weapons vault is.
Before we figure that out,
Madam won't let us kill him.
Tang Lian is his only disciple
as well as his weakness.
Tianlu.
Lock him up
somewhere for now.
I'll go report to Madam
about what just happened.
I'm back.
Well,
what did you find?
I snuck into the Tang Clan
and ran into Tang Lianyue's young disciple,
Tang Lian.
Only then did I learn
that Tang Lianyue has been trapped in the Lianyue Pavilion.
To protect me,
Tang Lian was caught
by Tang Tianlu and Tang Fulu.
We must go back and rescue them.
Don't panic, Yumo.
Tell me more about it.
Some unknown thing
has frozen Tang Lianyue solid.
Within three chi,
no living thing can approach me.
It's the Frostmoon Cocoon.
Miss Bai ever brought that up.
It's extremely rare,
but it can instantly freeze
even a master.
However, it doesn't last forever.
Perhaps they're there every day to replenish its effect,
keeping Tang Lianyue under control long-term.
As for why they don't kill him,
maybe they need
something from him.
Maybe
Qingyang and Xuewei
are inside the Tang Clan too.
Has something happened
to Qingyang and Xuewei?
Yes.
The Tang Clan
is truly a hostile place.
Although it's dangerous,
we must enter the Tang Clan again.
However, we need
to come up with a thorough plan first.
Those we sent to Jin City
haven't returned yet?
No.
We've lost contact
with both the new envoys
and the disciples stationed in Jin City.
We could still send Xuanwu Guardian missives then.
Now, even that's impossible.
So we believe
something major
is about to happen in Jin City.
If that's the case,
it must be tied to the Tang Clan.
What happens in the Tang Clan is a martial affair.
It has little to do with the Baixiao Hall.
Yet
Tang Lianyue
from the Tang Clan
is my close friend.
He's a man of principle,
so why hasn't he returned to Tianqi City
to report in a long time?
If the Tang Clan changes,
the entire martial world will change.
Any word from the Blood River?
Su Changhe, Su Muyu, and the rest
are already in Jin City.
However, we haven't heard from them
since then.
Just relying on the Blood River
won't put my mind at ease.
We need to send
someone capable and reliable
to the Tang Clan.
[Tang Clan is in turmoil.]
[Second City Lord, please go check on it on Guardian Azure Dragon's behalf. Ji.]
What a hassle.
It's been days.
These Tang Clan men just won't give up.
Could it be
this is where my life ends?
Go.
If there are any Blood River disciples in Jin City,
come to my rescue!
He's over there!
Give chase!
Looks like you're here
after being chased by your enemy.
Are you
from the Wangchengshan Sect?
Wangchengshan Sect?
Do I look like a Taoist to you?
Li.
Do I look like one?
Mister.
Saving a life
is a sacred act.
I have many rare treasures,
and I can trade them with you.
I'm not interested in that.
Just tell me
who your enemy is.
It's the Tang Clan.
Tang Clan?
You're in luck.
I won't ask your name
or where you're from.
If the Tang Clan wants you dead,
I'll save you.
Get on.
Where do you think you're running?
Thunder shakes the heavens and earth.
One strike splits the sky for ninety thousand miles!
Thank you for saving me.
Aren't you curious why I saved you
at the mention of the Tang Clan?
If you don't want to tell me,
I won't ask you.
Asking too many questions brings trouble
in this martial world.
You're a wise man.
My surname's Lei.
Lei...
Lei?
Lei as in Lei Fortress?
That's right.
The Lei Fortress
never gets along with the Tang Clan.
Causing them trouble now and then
sounds fun to me.
You're their enemy,
so I saved you.
You saved the right man, then.
If I make it out alive this time,
I'll be sure to give them some trouble
to repay your kindness.
[Refined Brew, Serene Mind]
Those are Soul-Calling Paper Butterflies.
Soul-Calling Paper Butterflies...
That must be Master Mu.
Yes.
Only Master Mu
can summon Soul-Calling Paper Butterflies.
When one appears,
the underworld gates open
and ten thousand butterflies follow.
Mu Qingyang resorted to this Soul-Calling Paper Butterfly.
Looks like
he...
That's good news.
Mu Qingyang is still alive.
But the bad news is
Mu Qingyang
is about to perish.
Let it lead us there.
Sure.
Wait for me here.
May I know your name, mister?
I must remember
the favor you've shown me.
My name is Lei Yunhe.
It's the Twin Cranes of Lei Clan.
I've heard of you.
What an honor.
I have some business to attend to,
so I must go now.
I hope you
will cause them trouble
as promised.
Li.
Let's go.
What an interesting man.
The Umbrella Ghost of the Blood River.
Who would've thought
I'd run into you here?
Elder Tang Tianlu of the Tang Clan.
We've met before.
Is this how
the Tang Clan
greet its guests?
Who would ever mistake the Umbrella Ghost of the Blood River
for a guest?
It's said
that you often appear
on cold, rainy nights.
Like how an underworld reaper
or a wandering soul would do.
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪
♪How many hidden feelings♪
♪Sink in silence deep?♪
♪Searching through the endless nights♪
♪Struggling on the edge of love and pain♪
♪Shadows crossing shadows♪
♪Whose name hides in your eyes?♪
♪When the wind blows, ask not when I shall return♪
♪Ask not when I shall return♪
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪